Hello, my friends, and welcome to exercise number forty.
And this exercise, we are asked to write a function to delete a node from Lincoln List at specific
position.
We have seen in the previous video about an exercise for 45.
Deleting and not but having a specific key was a specific key.
Now we need to delete the not with a specific position, so we gave the position of the node and be
deleted without specifying the key inside it.
OK, so and this is this is the way that we may use it more because we are interested in deleting in
that specific position and not deleting it.
Not with specific.
OK.
So we will start by creating a new method called delete.
Not OK.
It took int position
and delete node.
That position, I would name it.
And we start the first step is.
If Lincoln List is empty, we are checking if had equal equal to now, then return.
OK, this is a very important step to check.
Then that list is not empty or or it is empty.
No, it is not empty.
Then go to storing that.
They have no.
OK.
We need to keep the on that contains to have and to Taft in order to make that reference for overhead,
to keep the reference of our hat without losing this reference.
OK, now there, as as we have seen in the previous exercise, that we need to check if the head need
to be removed.
So if I am looking forward to the first, I'm going to remove the first.
Not so I'm going to remove the hat.
So if by removing had.
If position equal to one position, if position equal, equal to zero, then had equal had equal to
them the next.
OK.
It's very simple.
And Richter, we are changing the.
OK, changing ahead.
No.
Four.
If find finding the previous note of the note to be delayed, find the previous No.
Of they're known to be delayed.
OK.
It's very simple.
So Ford and I equal to zero.
The stamp does not equal to null
and I less than the position minus one.
It's very important.
I + +.
OK, this is how we make this -- equal to them.
But my God, next.
OK.
You see guys that we need to find the previous not to be there.
The previous nod of the not to be deleted.
It's very important because we need to understand what is the previous of this note.
OK.
No.
And my kid still answering to my room and they're learning data structure and algorithms.
Sorry, guys.
OK, well, that's a good thing if that position is more than number of knots.
OK, it's out of bounds.
If tamped that equal equal to null, then or this is very important.
Check so -- the next.
Equal equal to nothing.
Now it's where it can also.
OK.
That step number six is.
Specifying then not Dot, next dot next, I making it jumping.
So it is the not to be deleted, store the pointer to the next of the not to be deleted.
OK, storing.
Pointer to their next of nine to be deleted, none.
Next to be equal to them the next the next week and then the next equal to next.
It's very simple.
OK, let's try to make this happen.
The lead, not that position, I will.
Remove this, or no, I would just keep it because we can continue exercise No.
46, the lifting, not at specific position.
So think at least the delete, delete, not acquisition.
I need to delay position number four.
Let me see.
Let's run that.
And here we go.
Four, one, five and three.
The number six has been deleted successfully.
No list.
So I will comment this and see the list before deletion.
It have four, one, five, three and six.
I need to delete at index four.
OK, so what?
Zero, one, two, three and four.
OK.
I am deleting this.
Not not.
And it is deleted successfully from the.
This is how we delete them, not from that list.
Our using this.